Alyssa, Png Mobile: +65 87277005

Email: alyssapng@u.nus.edu LinkedIn/Github/Online Portfolio



#### **Personal Statement**

I am a second-year Computer Science student passionate about technology and motivated by an eagerness to learn. During my A\*STAR Institute of Chemical and Engineering Sciences internship, I diligently developed analytical skills, leading to co-authorship of a research article.

My sociable nature drives my passion for teamwork. In projects like Orbital and my Final Year Project, I proactively seek clarification and eagerly share my ideas. I view these interactions as opportunities to exchange knowledge and expose myself to diverse perspectives.

Being a program member of various Eusoff committees developed my ability to delegate tasks, inspire others through my actions and communicate effectively. These were vital in teaching at The Young Makers, where I developed decision-making and team management skills, boosting my confidence level.

Engaging in initiatives like Youth Expedition Project also deepened my compassion for others, aligning with my passion in helping people and contributing to the community. This inspired me to strive towards using my problem-solving skills and creativity to make a tangible impact to help others.

Embracing new experiences and challenging myself drives my continuous desire to grow. I am excited about contributing my knowledge and passion to innovate and join a team that shapes the future.

#### **Education**

Aug 2022 - Present National University of Singapore

Singapore

**Bachelor of Computer Science** 

**NUS Transcript** 

Aug 2019 - May 2022 Ngee Ann Polytechnic

Diploma in Biomedical Engineering

Ngee Ann Transcript

Singapore

#### **Work Experience**

Nov 2021 - Present

# **The Young Makers (TYM)**

Main Teacher

Singapore

- Taught two groups of 5 and 3 students each, aged 7-9 years old.
- Developed a curriculum including:
  - 1. Introduction to Python: 15 lessons, 737 slides
  - 2. Advanced Scratch: 10 lessons, 333 slides, aimed at enhancing student engagement and understanding.
- Improved communication skills by guiding students in creating around 10 projects per student, utilizing visual aids and clear step-by-step instructions.
- Strengthened troubleshooting abilities by assisting students in debugging and resolving project issues.

Mar 2021 – Aug 2021

# A\*STAR Institute of Chemical and Engineering Sciences

Singapore

Assistant R&D Engineer Intern

- Co-authored a research article, contributing to about 30% of the essential graphs and developing proficient analytical skills in the process.
- Improved research project efficiency by around 50% through conducting experiments independently and implementing an Excel calculation system.

Jan 2020 - Mar 2020

## Lady M Singapore

Singapore

Part-Time Staff:

- Improved crowd management process to manage more than 50 people in queues at any point in time by working efficiently under pressure.
- Proactively took the initiative to learn and carry out multiple roles such as barista, cake cutter and waitress.

# Achievements/Co-curricular Activities/Volunteering

June 2023 - Present

#### **National University Singapore Football Varsity:**

Singapore

Represented NUS for 2023 SUNIG Games

Aug 2023 - Sep 2023

#### Hack for Cities 2023 Hackathon

Singapore

- Attained a top 16 placement.
- Proposed to use Quantum Computing to improve smart parking through efficient tracking of vacancies and predictive analysis.

May 2023 - Aug 2023

## Orbital 2023: Productivity App

Singapore

- Created user-friendly UI/UX with React Native and Expo Go. ensuring easy navigation for users.
- Implemented a React Native Countdown Timer to track study hours, storing data on Firebase, and presenting it as bar graphs to track yearly, monthly, and weekly progress.
- Established an authentication system using Firebase Authentication.

April 2023

## **Top Field Award Rookie of The Year**

Singapore

in recognition of invaluable services rendered to Eusoff Hall for the academic year 2022/2023

Aug 2022 - Aug 2023

#### **Eusoff Hall**

Singapore

- Hall Promotion Board:
  - Organized Eusoff Hall Engagement Camp
- Culture Management Committee
  - Planned and Emceed for Culture Events
- Green Committee
  - Conduct environmentally friendly activities
- Participated in the Inter-hall Games and placed 1<sup>st</sup> for Ultimate Frisbee and Football

May 2022

#### Smitech Asia Sliver Medal & Prize

Singapore

Second most outstanding graduate in the Diploma in Biomedical

Engineering course

Sep 2021 –	Jan	2022
------------	-----	------

# Final Year Project (FYP): Augmented Reality Telepresence Robot

- Leveraged Raspberry Pi, Vue.js, and Amazon Web Services (AWS)
- Facilitated real-time audio and video streaming from the robot's camera to a Vue.js website through AWS Kinesis Video Streams with WebRTC integration.
- Implemented user authentication using AWS IoT Core credentials, enabling individual user connections to distinct robots.
- Enabled robot movement control via AWS IoT Core MQTT topics through AWS API Gateway

Aug 2021 – Oct 2022

#### East Youth:

Singapore

Singapore

- Participated in Food Distribution Events consisting of collecting non-perishables from donors and distributing to over 50 lower-income households.
- Communicating with potential donors, educating them about our Food Distribution Event and answering any queries.

June 2020 A\*star Science Award

Singapore

recognizes students who have shown interest and excellence in the Sciences and Mathematics.

Apr 2019 – Apr 2022

#### Ngee Ann Polytechnic Ultimate Frisbee:

Singapore

- 2<sup>nd</sup> place in the 2022 PO-LITE games
- 4<sup>th</sup> place in the 2019 PO-LITE games
- Plate champion in Ultyschool 2020

Aug 2019 - Sep 2019

# Youth Expedition Program Vietnam (Hoi An) Sep 2019

Vietnam

- Student Leader
- Service-learning overseas trip
- Volunteered at the Touch Home Care

# IT & Software Proficiency

Office Productivity	Microsoft Word, PowerPoint Microsoft Excel	Proficient Proficient
Data Analysis	Origin Lab Radiant	Proficient Intermediate
Engineering	Breadboarding Soldering skills Embedded Systems	Proficient Proficient Basic
Web	HTML, CSS React Native	Basic Intermediate
Database	Firebase AWS Cloud Services	Proficient Intermediate
Programming	Java C C# Python	Proficient Intermediate Basic Intermediate

Scripting JavaScript Intermediate

Robotics Raspberry PI Intermediate

Arduino Intermediate Micro-bit Intermediate

# Language Proficiency

SpokenEnglish – fluent; Simplified Chinese – competentWrittenEnglish – competent; Simplified Chinese – fair